<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>《创伤》白求恩</title>
    <link>https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/124</link>
    <description>头顶上煤油灯像白炽的蜂房，嗡嗡作响。土墙，土地，土炕，白纸窗户。屋内弥漫着血腥味和三氯甲烷味。天气很冷。在华北地区的灵丘附近，12月1日凌晨3点与八路军在一起。

负伤的人们。

伤口就像干涸的小池塘，结成了一块黑褐色的土；伤口边缘裂开，四周有一些黑色的蛆了；整洁的伤口的深处隐藏着脓肿，脓肿就像一条决堤的河，在坚硬的大块肌肉中奔流，像一条温泉，在肌肉周围和中间流淌；伤口向外扩大，把令人恐怖的肉质兰花和麝香石竹分别地腐蚀和碾碎。黑色的血块从伤口中喷出，混杂着令人恶心的气泡，在二次大出血造成的血流中漂浮。

凝固的血把又旧又脏的绷带粘在皮肤上，小心点，最好先将它弄湿。从腿后边过去，把腿抬高点。整条腿为什么会软得像一个包，像一个扯松的长筒袜？什么样的长筒袜？是圣诞节为孩子装礼物的那种长筒袜。那个坚硬的细骨枝在哪里？它被打成了许多碎片。用你的手指把他们捡出来。它们白的像狗牙，尖利而又参差不齐。好了，摸一下，还留下碎片了吗？喔，这里有。全都取出来了？是的。不，这里还有一个。这儿的肌肉坏死了吗？刺刺它。是的，它坏死了。切除它。那它怎么愈合呀？这些肌肉曾经如此强壮，而现在是这样的破损和腐烂，它们怎样才能恢复以往的强韧呢？拉，放松，拉，放松，多么有趣呀！现在完成了，好了，做完了。现在，我们已经被毁灭了，我们自己可怎么办呀？

下一个。一个未成年人，17岁！子弹穿腹而过。三氯甲烷准备好了吗？恶臭从敞开的腹膜孔中扑面而来，是粪便的气味。一圈圈的肠子肿得呈粉红色，上面有4个穿孔。把它们缝合起来，把结实的缝线皱拢，用海绵吸骨盆。试管，3个试管。很难缝合。给他保温。怎么保温？把这些砖放到热水里去。

蛆是一种狡猾的爬行动物。这人还活着吗？是的，他还活着。用学术用语来说，他还活着。给他输液，也许他身体无数细小的细胞将能回忆，它们可能回忆起那火热咸味的海，它们的祖宅和第一份食物；它们有着一百万年的记忆，可能会记起其他的潮汐，其他的海洋和由海洋和太阳孕育的生物。这可以使它们抬起疲倦的头，深深地吸一口气，努力地复苏。这是可能的。

这一位。再次秋收时，他还能在路上一边赶着骡子跑，一边欢快地叫喊吗？不，那个人不再会跑了，一条腿的人怎么能跑呢？那他怎么办哪？他只能坐着看别的孩子跑动。他在想什么呢？他在想你我所想。可怜有什么用呢？不要可怜他！可怜会贬低他所做的牺牲，他这样做是为了保卫中国。帮帮他吧，把他从桌上移开，把他抱在怀里，他轻的像个孩子。是的，他就是你的孩子，是我的孩子。

多美的身体呀，各个部分都那么完美，动起来时是那么灵巧、那么柔顺、那么有生气和强壮，但是一旦它们伤残了，又是多么可怕。微弱的生命之光越来越弱，就像蜡烛一样摇曳了一下熄灭了，静静的、轻轻地。熄灭时它做了反抗，然后屈服了，它有权利说话，最后还是沉默了。

![image|400x248](upload://lu4fdh3TwvzeGxIVVmGqYxYvE3R.jpeg) 

还有吗？四个日本战俘。带他们进来，在这个痛苦的群体中没有敌我之分，切开那带血的制服，给他们止血，把他们平放在其他伤员旁边。哎呀，他们像兄弟一样！这些士兵都是职业杀手吗？不是，他们只是业余的士兵。劳动者的手，他们是穿着军装的地道的劳动者。

没有新的伤员了。早晨6点。天哪！屋里真冷。打开门，远方青山如黛。东方开始泛白了，再过一个小时太阳就会升起。上床睡觉吧。

但是，没有睡意。这种残忍，这种愚蠢的原因是什么的？一百万工人从日本来屠杀、残害成千上万的中国人，为什么日本工人要攻击他的中国工人兄弟、迫使他们不得不奋起自卫呢？中国人的死对日本工人有好处吗？没有，他们怎么会有所收获呢？那么，上帝呀，谁将获利呢？谁又应该对派日本工人来中国执行这种杀戮使命负责呢？谁将从中牟利？怎么可能劝说日本工人来攻击中国工人——他们贫苦生活中的兄弟，痛苦中的同伴啊？

一小部分富人，一个人数不多的阶层有没有可能劝说一百万穷人进攻并试图毁灭一百万像他们自己一样贫穷的人、以便富人更加富有呢？这是一个可怕的想法！他们是如何劝说这些穷人来到中国的？告诉他们真相吗？没有，假如他们知道真相，绝对不会来到中国的。这些富人敢告诉工人们他们只是想得到廉价原料、更大的市场和更多的利润吗？不，他们只是告诉工人们这场战争是为了“种族命运”、是为了“天皇的荣耀”和“国家的荣誉”，是为了他们的“天皇与国家”。

荒谬！绝对的荒谬！

这样一场战争的代理人一定得像其他犯罪如杀人犯的代理人一样，必须从可能获利的人中挑选出来。8000万日本工人、贫困的农民和失业的工人会从中获利吗？从西班牙侵略墨西哥、英格兰侵略印度到意大利侵占埃塞俄比亚，在整个侵略战争史上，这些所谓的“胜利”国家的工人得到过好处吗？没有，他们从来没有从战争中获得过利益。

日本工人从本国的自然资源、黄金、白银、铁、煤和油中就获得利益吗？很久以前，他们就不再拥有自然资源了。因为，它们是属于富人、统治阶级的，成百上千的矿工们仍生活在贫困之中。那么，他们又怎么可能通过武装掠夺中国的金、银、铁、煤和油而获利呢？难道一个国家的富人不是为了自己的利益才占有其他国家的财富？难道他们不一直这样做吗？

日本军国主义者和资产阶级是唯一可能通过大屠杀和经过授权的疯狂行为而获利的阶级，这一点似乎是不可避免的。正是这些假神圣的刽子手，那些统治阶级从这场战争中获得了利益，但是却让整个国家受到指控。

那么，侵略战争和征服殖民地的战争只是件“大生意”吗？是的，看起来如此。但是，这些民族罪犯中许多为非作歹者都试图把他们的真实目的藏在高度抽象和理想的旗帜下，通过谋杀或制造战争来抢夺市场，通过劫掠来得到原料。他们发现，偷比交换更廉价，屠杀比交易更容易，这是这场战争的秘密，也是所有战争的秘密——利润、生意、利润、带血的钱。

这一切后面，存在着那个令人恐怖和欲壑难填的“生意与血腥”瘟神，它的名字就叫“利润”。金钱就像一个无法满足的摩洛克神，要求利润与回报，它为了满足贪欲为所欲为，甚至不惜杀害几百万人。在日本军队后面站着军国主义者，在军国主义者后面站着金融资本和资本家。他们是血脉兄弟，是同谋。

这些人类敌人像什么呢？他们会在前额上贴上一个标记，让人们轻易就能辨认出他们，躲避他们，骂他们是罪犯吗？不！相反，他们是受人尊敬的人物，他们荣誉在身，有绅士称号，他们也自称为绅士。多么滑稽的名字！绅士？他们是国家、社会和教会的支柱，他们从过多的财富中拿出一部分来支持公共和私人的慈善事业，他们向机构捐赠。在私生活中，他们善良而体贴。他们遵纪守法，遵守的是保护他们的法律——财产法。但是，有一个迹象可以辨认出这些持枪的绅士：只要威胁说要减少他们的钱所带来的利润，他们就会像猛兽一样咆哮着醒来，像野人一样无情、像疯子一样残忍、像刽子手一样残暴。如果人类想要存在，这些人必须消失，只要他们活着，世界上就不会有持久的和平。允许他们存在的那个人类社会的组织必须废除。

正是这些人造成了创伤。</description>
    <language>zh-CN</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 01:27:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>文献 | 书籍</category>
    <atom:link href="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/124.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>《创伤》白求恩</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[msc]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <h2>
<a name="wounds-1" class="anchor" href="https://mlmmlm.icu#wounds-1"></a>Wounds</h2>
<p>The kerosene lamp overhead makes a steady buzzing sound like an incandescent hive of bees. Mud walls. Mud floor. Mud bed. White paper windows. Smell of blood and chloroform. Cold. Three o’clock in the morning, Dec. i, North China, near Lin Chu, with the 8th Route Army.</p>
<p>Men with wounds.</p>
<p>Wounds like little dried pools, caked with black-brown earth; wounds with torn edges frilled with black gangrene; neat wounds, concealing beneath the abscess in their depths, burrowing into and around the great firm muscles like a dammed-back river, running around and between the muscles like a hot stream; wounds, expanding outward, decaying orchids or crushed carnations, terrible flowers of flesh; wounds from which the dark blood is spewed out in clots, mixed with the ominous gas bubbles, floating on the fresh flood of the still­continuing secondary haemorrhage.</p>
<p>Old filthy bandages stuck to the skin with blood-glue. Careful. Better moisten first. Through the thigh. Pick the leg up. Why it’s like a bag, a long, loose, red stocking. What kind of stocking? A Christmas stocking. Where’s that fine, strong rod of bone now? In a dozen pieces. Pick them out with your fingers; white as dog’s teeth, sharp and jagged. Now feel. Any more left? Yes, here. All? Yes, no, here’s another piece. Is this muscle dead? Pinch it. Yes, it’s dead. Cut it out. How can that heal? How can those muscles, once so strong, now so torn, so devastated, so ruined, resume their proud tension? Pull, relax. Pull, relax. What fun it was! Now that is finished. Now that’s done. Now we are destroyed. Now what will we do with ourselves?</p>
<p>Next. What an infant! Seventeen. Shot through the belly. Chloroform. Ready? Gas rushes out of the open peritoneal cavity. Odour of faeces. Pink coils of distended intestine. Four perforations. Close them. Purse strong suture. Sponge out the pelvis. Tube. Three tubes. Hard to close. Keep him warm. How? Dip those bricks into hot water.</p>
<p>Gangrene is a cunning, creeping fellow. Is this one alive? Yes, he lives. Technically speaking, he is alive. Give him saline intravenously. Per­haps the innumerable tiny cells of his body will remember. They may remember the hot, salty sea, their ancestral home, their first food. With the memory of a million years, they may remember other tides, other oceans and life being born of the sea and sun. It may make them raise their tired little heads, drink deep and struggle back into life again. It may do that.</p>
<p>And this one. Will he run along the road beside his mule at another harvest, with cries of pleasure and happiness? No, that one will never run again. How can you run with one leg? What will he do? Why, he’ll sit and watch other boys run. What will he think? He’ll think what you and I would think. What’s the good of pity? Don’t pity him! Pity would diminish his sacrifice. He did this for the defence of China. Help him. Lift him off the table. Carry him in your arms. Why, he’s as light as a child! Yes, your child, my child.</p>
<p>How beautiful the body is; how perfect its parts; with what precision it moves; how obedient; proud and strong. How terrible when torn. The little flame of life sinks lower and lower, and, with a flicker, goes out. It goes out like a candle goes out. Quietly and gently. It makes its protest at extinction, then submits. It has its say, then is silent.</p>
<p>Any more? Four Japanese prisoners. Bring them in. In this community of pain, there are no enemies. Cut away that blood-stained uniform. Stop that haemorrhage. Lay them beside the others. Why, they’re alike as brothers! Are these soldiers professional man-killers? No, these are amateurs-in-arms. Workman’s hands. These are workers-in-uniform.</p>
<p>No more. Six o’clock in the morning. God, it’s cold in this room. Open the door. Over the distant, dark-blue mountains, a pale, faint line of light appears in the East. In an hour the sun will be up. To bed and sleep.</p>
<p>But sleep will not come. What is the cause of this cruelty, this stupid­ity? A million workmen come from Japan to kill or mutilate a million Chinese workmen. Why should the Japanese worker attack his brother worker, who is forced merely to defend himself? Will the Japanese worker benefit by the death of the Chinese? No, how can he gain? Then, in God’s name, who will gain? Who is responsible for sending these Jap­anese workmen on this murderous mission? Who will profit from it? How was it possible to persuade the Japanese workman to attack the Chinese workman - his brother in poverty; his companion in misery?</p>
<p>Is it possible that a few rich men, a small class of men, have persuaded a million poor men to attack, and attempt to destroy, another million men as poor as they? So that the rich may be richer still? Terrible thought! How did they persuade these poor men to come to China? By telling them the truth? No, they would never have come if they had known the truth. Did they dare to tell these workmen that the rich only wanted cheaper raw materials, more markets and more profit? No, they told them that this brutal war was ‘The Destiny of the Race,’ it was for the ‘Glory of the Emperor,’ it was for the ‘Honour of the State,’ it was for their ‘King and Country.’</p>
<p>False. False as Hell!</p>
<p>The agents of a criminal war of aggression, such as this, must be looked for like the agents of other crimes, such as murder, among those who are likely to benefit from those crimes. Will the 80,000,000 workers of Japan, the poor farmers, the unemployed industrial workers - will they gain? In the entire history of Wars of Aggression, from the Con­quest of Mexico by Spain, the capture of India by England, the rape of Ethiopia by Italy, have the workers of those ‘victorious’ countries ever been known to benefit? No, these never benefit by such wars.</p>
<p>Does the Japanese workman benefit by the natural resources of even his own country, by the gold, the silver, the iron, the coal, the oil? Long ago he ceased to possess that natural wealth. It belongs to the rich, the ruling class. The millions who work those mines live in poverty. So how is he likely to benefit by the armed robbery of the gold, silver, iron, coal and oil of China? Will not the rich owners of the one retain, for their own profit, the wealth of the other? Have they not always done so?</p>
<p>It would seem inescapable that the militarists and the capitalists of Japan are the only class likely to gain by this mass murder, this autho­rized madness. That sanctified butcher; that ruling class, the true State stands accused.</p>
<p>Are wars of aggression, wars for the conquest of colonies, then just Big Business? Yes, it would seem so, however much the perpetrators of such national crimes seek to hide their true purpose under the banners of high-sounding abstractions and ideals. They make war to capture markets by murder; raw materials by rape. They find it cheaper to steal than to exchange; easier to butcher than to buy. This is the secret of this war. It is the secret of all wars. Profit. Business. Profit. Blood money.</p>
<p>Behind all stands that terrible, implacable God of Business and Blood, whose name is Profit. Money, like an insatiable Moloch, demands its interest, its return, and will stop at nothing, not even the murder of mil­lions, to satisfy its greed. Behind the army stand the militarists. Behind the militarists stand finance capital and the capitalist. Brothers in blood: companions in crime.</p>
<p>What do these enemies of the human race look like? Do they wear on their foreheads a sign so that they may be told, shunned and con­demned as criminals? No. On the contrary, they are the respectable ones. They are honoured. They call themselves, and are called, gentle­men. What a travesty on the name! Gentlemen! They are the pillars of the State, of the church, of society. They support private and public charity out of the excess of their wealth. They endow institutions. In their private lives they are kind and considerate. They obey the law, their law, the law of property. But there is one sign by which these gen­tle gunmen can be told. Threaten a reduction on the profit of their money and the beast in them awakes with a snarl. They become as ruth­less as savages, brutal as madmen, remorseless as executioners. Such men as these must perish if the human race is to continue. There can be no permanent peace in the world while they live. Such an organization of human society as permits them to exist must be abolished.</p>
<p>These men make the wounds.</p>
          <p><a href="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/124/3">阅读完整话题</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/124/3</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 01:27:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">mlmmlm.icu-post-124-3</guid>
        <source url="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/124.rss">《创伤》白求恩</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>《创伤》白求恩</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[msc]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a class="attachment" href="https://mlmmlm.icu/uploads/short-url/rfQr5edq7xXmn0JTjEl0aUoPL5P.pdf">The Politics of Passion Norman Bethunes Writing and Art .pdf</a> (4.9 MB)</p>
          <p><a href="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/124/2">阅读完整话题</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/124/2</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 01:23:59 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">mlmmlm.icu-post-124-2</guid>
        <source url="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/124.rss">《创伤》白求恩</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>《创伤》白求恩</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[msc]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>头顶上煤油灯像白炽的蜂房，嗡嗡作响。土墙，土地，土炕，白纸窗户。屋内弥漫着血腥味和三氯甲烷味。天气很冷。在华北地区的灵丘附近，12月1日凌晨3点与八路军在一起。</p>
<p>负伤的人们。</p>
<p>伤口就像干涸的小池塘，结成了一块黑褐色的土；伤口边缘裂开，四周有一些黑色的蛆了；整洁的伤口的深处隐藏着脓肿，脓肿就像一条决堤的河，在坚硬的大块肌肉中奔流，像一条温泉，在肌肉周围和中间流淌；伤口向外扩大，把令人恐怖的肉质兰花和麝香石竹分别地腐蚀和碾碎。黑色的血块从伤口中喷出，混杂着令人恶心的气泡，在二次大出血造成的血流中漂浮。</p>
<p>凝固的血把又旧又脏的绷带粘在皮肤上，小心点，最好先将它弄湿。从腿后边过去，把腿抬高点。整条腿为什么会软得像一个包，像一个扯松的长筒袜？什么样的长筒袜？是圣诞节为孩子装礼物的那种长筒袜。那个坚硬的细骨枝在哪里？它被打成了许多碎片。用你的手指把他们捡出来。它们白的像狗牙，尖利而又参差不齐。好了，摸一下，还留下碎片了吗？喔，这里有。全都取出来了？是的。不，这里还有一个。这儿的肌肉坏死了吗？刺刺它。是的，它坏死了。切除它。那它怎么愈合呀？这些肌肉曾经如此强壮，而现在是这样的破损和腐烂，它们怎样才能恢复以往的强韧呢？拉，放松，拉，放松，多么有趣呀！现在完成了，好了，做完了。现在，我们已经被毁灭了，我们自己可怎么办呀？</p>
<p>下一个。一个未成年人，17岁！子弹穿腹而过。三氯甲烷准备好了吗？恶臭从敞开的腹膜孔中扑面而来，是粪便的气味。一圈圈的肠子肿得呈粉红色，上面有4个穿孔。把它们缝合起来，把结实的缝线皱拢，用海绵吸骨盆。试管，3个试管。很难缝合。给他保温。怎么保温？把这些砖放到热水里去。</p>
<p>蛆是一种狡猾的爬行动物。这人还活着吗？是的，他还活着。用学术用语来说，他还活着。给他输液，也许他身体无数细小的细胞将能回忆，它们可能回忆起那火热咸味的海，它们的祖宅和第一份食物；它们有着一百万年的记忆，可能会记起其他的潮汐，其他的海洋和由海洋和太阳孕育的生物。这可以使它们抬起疲倦的头，深深地吸一口气，努力地复苏。这是可能的。</p>
<p>这一位。再次秋收时，他还能在路上一边赶着骡子跑，一边欢快地叫喊吗？不，那个人不再会跑了，一条腿的人怎么能跑呢？那他怎么办哪？他只能坐着看别的孩子跑动。他在想什么呢？他在想你我所想。可怜有什么用呢？不要可怜他！可怜会贬低他所做的牺牲，他这样做是为了保卫中国。帮帮他吧，把他从桌上移开，把他抱在怀里，他轻的像个孩子。是的，他就是你的孩子，是我的孩子。</p>
<p>多美的身体呀，各个部分都那么完美，动起来时是那么灵巧、那么柔顺、那么有生气和强壮，但是一旦它们伤残了，又是多么可怕。微弱的生命之光越来越弱，就像蜡烛一样摇曳了一下熄灭了，静静的、轻轻地。熄灭时它做了反抗，然后屈服了，它有权利说话，最后还是沉默了。</p>
<p><img src="https://mlmmlm.icu/uploads/default/original/1X/9693c897872b24cf52fbc09aaf6566f18508a537.jpeg" alt="image" data-base62-sha1="lu4fdh3TwvzeGxIVVmGqYxYvE3R" width="400" height="248"></p>
<p>还有吗？四个日本战俘。带他们进来，在这个痛苦的群体中没有敌我之分，切开那带血的制服，给他们止血，把他们平放在其他伤员旁边。哎呀，他们像兄弟一样！这些士兵都是职业杀手吗？不是，他们只是业余的士兵。劳动者的手，他们是穿着军装的地道的劳动者。</p>
<p>没有新的伤员了。早晨6点。天哪！屋里真冷。打开门，远方青山如黛。东方开始泛白了，再过一个小时太阳就会升起。上床睡觉吧。</p>
<p>但是，没有睡意。这种残忍，这种愚蠢的原因是什么的？一百万工人从日本来屠杀、残害成千上万的中国人，为什么日本工人要攻击他的中国工人兄弟、迫使他们不得不奋起自卫呢？中国人的死对日本工人有好处吗？没有，他们怎么会有所收获呢？那么，上帝呀，谁将获利呢？谁又应该对派日本工人来中国执行这种杀戮使命负责呢？谁将从中牟利？怎么可能劝说日本工人来攻击中国工人——他们贫苦生活中的兄弟，痛苦中的同伴啊？</p>
<p>一小部分富人，一个人数不多的阶层有没有可能劝说一百万穷人进攻并试图毁灭一百万像他们自己一样贫穷的人、以便富人更加富有呢？这是一个可怕的想法！他们是如何劝说这些穷人来到中国的？告诉他们真相吗？没有，假如他们知道真相，绝对不会来到中国的。这些富人敢告诉工人们他们只是想得到廉价原料、更大的市场和更多的利润吗？不，他们只是告诉工人们这场战争是为了“种族命运”、是为了“天皇的荣耀”和“国家的荣誉”，是为了他们的“天皇与国家”。</p>
<p>荒谬！绝对的荒谬！</p>
<p>这样一场战争的代理人一定得像其他犯罪如杀人犯的代理人一样，必须从可能获利的人中挑选出来。8000万日本工人、贫困的农民和失业的工人会从中获利吗？从西班牙侵略墨西哥、英格兰侵略印度到意大利侵占埃塞俄比亚，在整个侵略战争史上，这些所谓的“胜利”国家的工人得到过好处吗？没有，他们从来没有从战争中获得过利益。</p>
<p>日本工人从本国的自然资源、黄金、白银、铁、煤和油中就获得利益吗？很久以前，他们就不再拥有自然资源了。因为，它们是属于富人、统治阶级的，成百上千的矿工们仍生活在贫困之中。那么，他们又怎么可能通过武装掠夺中国的金、银、铁、煤和油而获利呢？难道一个国家的富人不是为了自己的利益才占有其他国家的财富？难道他们不一直这样做吗？</p>
<p>日本军国主义者和资产阶级是唯一可能通过大屠杀和经过授权的疯狂行为而获利的阶级，这一点似乎是不可避免的。正是这些假神圣的刽子手，那些统治阶级从这场战争中获得了利益，但是却让整个国家受到指控。</p>
<p>那么，侵略战争和征服殖民地的战争只是件“大生意”吗？是的，看起来如此。但是，这些民族罪犯中许多为非作歹者都试图把他们的真实目的藏在高度抽象和理想的旗帜下，通过谋杀或制造战争来抢夺市场，通过劫掠来得到原料。他们发现，偷比交换更廉价，屠杀比交易更容易，这是这场战争的秘密，也是所有战争的秘密——利润、生意、利润、带血的钱。</p>
<p>这一切后面，存在着那个令人恐怖和欲壑难填的“生意与血腥”瘟神，它的名字就叫“利润”。金钱就像一个无法满足的摩洛克神，要求利润与回报，它为了满足贪欲为所欲为，甚至不惜杀害几百万人。在日本军队后面站着军国主义者，在军国主义者后面站着金融资本和资本家。他们是血脉兄弟，是同谋。</p>
<p>这些人类敌人像什么呢？他们会在前额上贴上一个标记，让人们轻易就能辨认出他们，躲避他们，骂他们是罪犯吗？不！相反，他们是受人尊敬的人物，他们荣誉在身，有绅士称号，他们也自称为绅士。多么滑稽的名字！绅士？他们是国家、社会和教会的支柱，他们从过多的财富中拿出一部分来支持公共和私人的慈善事业，他们向机构捐赠。在私生活中，他们善良而体贴。他们遵纪守法，遵守的是保护他们的法律——财产法。但是，有一个迹象可以辨认出这些持枪的绅士：只要威胁说要减少他们的钱所带来的利润，他们就会像猛兽一样咆哮着醒来，像野人一样无情、像疯子一样残忍、像刽子手一样残暴。如果人类想要存在，这些人必须消失，只要他们活着，世界上就不会有持久的和平。允许他们存在的那个人类社会的组织必须废除。</p>
<p>正是这些人造成了创伤。</p>
          <p><a href="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/124/1">阅读完整话题</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/124/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 13:21:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">mlmmlm.icu-post-124-1</guid>
        <source url="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/124.rss">《创伤》白求恩</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
