<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>ＲＤＸ 的合成工艺研究进展</title>
    <link>https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/1485</link>
    <description>[RDX的合成工艺研究进展.pdf|attachment](upload://f2HBxfIWVbYg798avwpQoAdhs0L.pdf) (593.0 KB)</description>
    <language>zh-CN</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 06:28:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>技术</category>
    <atom:link href="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/1485.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>ＲＤＸ 的合成工艺研究进展</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[azide]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>特质黑索今的制备方法 CN102887865A</p>
<p><a href="https://patents.google.com/patent/US4638065A/en" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">US4638065A</a> * 1984-04-04 1987-01-20 Aktiebolaget Bofors Crystallization method for HMX and RDX</p>
<p><a href="https://patents.google.com/patent/CN102887865A/ru#" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">CN100567272C</a> * 2007-04-17 2009-12-09 中北大学 一种制备黑索今的方法</p>
<p><a href="https://patents.google.com/patent/CN102887865A/ru#" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">CN101973947A</a> * 2010-09-25 2011-02-16 北京理工大学 一种用结晶控制技术制备球形化黑索今的方法</p>
<p><a href="https://patents.google.com/patent/CN102887865A/ru#" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">CN101979384A</a> * 2010-12-04 2011-02-23 北京理工大学 硝酸溶蚀制备球形化黑索今的方法</p>
<p>李伟明等: “黑索今结晶工艺对其撞击感度的影响研究”, 《天津化工》, vol. 22, no. 6, 30 November 2008 (2008-11-30), pages 41 - 43 *</p>
<p>王建龙等: “重结晶制备粉体RDX工艺研究”, 《华北工学院学报》, vol. 18, no. 3, 30 September 1997 (1997-09-30), pages 264 - 265 *</p>
<p>荆昌伦等: “硝酸重结晶法制备导爆管用黑索今研究”, 《兵工学报》, vol. 31, no. 1, 31 January 2010 (2010-01-31), pages 95 *</p>
<p>荆昌伦等: “粒经150～180μm球形RDX生产工艺”, 《含能材料》, vol. 17, no. 2, 15 April 2009 (2009-04-15) *</p>
<p>马东旭等: “重结晶制备奥克托今（HMX）粒经及晶形的研究”, 《陕西科技大学学报》, vol. 27, no. 1, 25 February 2009 (2009-02-25) *</p>
<p>黄文尧，颜事龙: “《炸药化学与制造》”, 31 March 2009, article “3.2 黑索今和奥克托今”, pages: 42 *</p>
<p>改性黑索今的生产方法 CN102887866B</p>
<h3>
<a name="patent-citations-3-1" class="anchor" href="https://mlmmlm.icu#patent-citations-3-1"></a>Patent Citations (3)</h3>
<p>Publication number Priority date Publication date Assignee Title</p>
<p>Family To Family Citations</p>
<p><a href="https://patents.google.com/patent/CN102887866B/zh#" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">SE451718B</a> * 1984-04-04 1987-10-26 Nobel Kemi Ab Sett att omkristallisera sprengemnena oktogen och hexogen</p>
<p><a href="https://patents.google.com/patent/CN102887866B/zh#" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">CN100567272C</a> * 2007-04-17 2009-12-09 中北大学 一种制备黑索今的方法</p>
<p><a href="https://patents.google.com/patent/CN102887866B/zh#" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">CN101979384B</a> * 2010-12-04 2015-03-04 北京理工大学 硝酸溶蚀制备球形化黑索今的方法</p>
          <p><a href="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/1485/4">阅读完整话题</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/1485/4</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 06:23:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">mlmmlm.icu-post-1485-4</guid>
        <source url="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/1485.rss">ＲＤＸ 的合成工艺研究进展</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>ＲＤＸ 的合成工艺研究进展</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[azide]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Thermal safety study on the synthesis of HMX by nitrourea method<br>
<a class="attachment" href="https://mlmmlm.icu/uploads/short-url/vLcJ9RpDT3cCAQ2idkBqJ5mcHid.pdf">wang2020.pdf</a> (1.9 MB)</p>
          <p><a href="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/1485/3">阅读完整话题</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/1485/3</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 05:06:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">mlmmlm.icu-post-1485-3</guid>
        <source url="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/1485.rss">ＲＤＸ 的合成工艺研究进展</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>ＲＤＸ 的合成工艺研究进展</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[azide]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><strong>Experimental</strong></p>
<p><strong>Hexamethylenetetramine Dinitrate</strong>—The method of preparation of this salt was essentially that described by Hale.° To a solution of 40 g. of hexamethylenetetramine in 70 ml. of water cooled in an ice-salt-bath was added drop-wise with stirring 43.5 ml. of 70% nitric acid; the tem­perature was not allowed to go above 15 °. After the mix­ture had been chilled for fifteen minutes at 5 °, the dinitrate was collected by filtration or by centrifuging. After being dried below 30 ° (low humidity necessary if air dried), the salt weighed 69.8 <em>g.</em> (92%). The filtrate, if kept be­low 15° at all times, can be used repeatedly. From 120 g. of hexamethylenetetramine 217 g. (95%) of the salt was obtained.</p>
<p><strong>六亚甲基四胺二硝酸盐</strong>——该盐的制备方法基本上是 Hale 所描述的。<sup>6</sup> 向在冰盐浴中冷却的 40 g 六亚甲基四胺在 70 ml 水中的溶液中滴加 搅拌 43.5 ml 70% 硝酸； 温度不允许超过15°。混合物在5°下冷却15分钟后，通过过滤或离心收集二硝酸盐。 在低于 30° 干燥后（如果空气干燥则需要低湿度），盐重 69.8 克（92%）。 滤液如果始终保持在 15° 以下，可重复使用。 从120克六亚甲基四胺中得到217克（95%）的盐。</p>
<p><strong>Preparation of RDX.</strong> —A 2-liter, four-necked, round-bottomed flask was equipped with an efficient mechanical stirrer, a thermometer, a 175-ml. buret which was marked off into 75 7-ml. graduations, and a powder funnel. The flask was set into a small-volume water-bath which fitted the flask fairly snugly and thus contained little water in order that the temperature could be changed quickly by the addition of cold water or steam through inlet tubes. An intimate mixture of 192 g. of hexamethylenetetramine di-nitrate and 114 g. of finely divided ammonium nitrate (dried at 80°) was weighed into 75 portions of 4.0-4.1 g. each (placed in test-tubes for convenience and protection) . A mixture of acetic anhydride-nitric acid was prepared by the dropwise addition with cooling (5-15°) and stirring of 78 ml. of 98% nitric acid to 480 ml. of acetic anhydride. This solution should be used as soon as it is prepared.</p>
<p><strong>RDX的制备</strong>  ——一个 2 升四颈圆底烧瓶配备有高效机械搅拌器、温度计、标为 75 个 7 毫升刻度的 175 毫升滴定管和一个粉末漏斗。将烧瓶放入一个小体积的水浴中，该水浴与烧瓶大小恰好合适，因此含有很少的水，以便通过入口管添加冷水或蒸汽来快速改变温度。将 192 克六亚甲基四胺二硝酸盐和 114 克细碎硝酸铵（在 80° 下干燥）的紧密混合物称重成 75 份，每份 4.0-4.1 克（为了方便和保护而放在试管中）。通过在冷却（5-15°）和搅拌下滴加78毫升来制备乙酸酐-硝酸的混合物。将 98% 的硝酸加到 480 ml 的乙酸酐中。该溶液应在制备后立即使用。</p>
<p>A 20-25 ml. portion of the acetic anhydride-nitric acid solution and about 1 g. of the solid mixture (which inhibits reaction between the anhydride and nitric acid as the tem­perature is raised and prevents a possible dangerous fume-off) was stirred in the flask and the temperature of the bath was raised quickly to about 80 ° by introducing steam into the water-bath. As soon as the internal temperature reached 70-75°, the solid and the liquid mixtures were added gradually at such a rate that a 4-g. portion of the mixture of solids was added for every 7 ml. of liquid. Throughout the exothermic reaction the inside temperature was maintained at 73-78 °. At the start it was necessary to proceed cautiously, but as the volume of the reaction mixture increased the temperature was easily kept within the desired limits when the additions were made as rapidly as a portion every half minute. After all of the reagents<br>
had been added, the mixture was stirred for fifteen minutes<br>
at 75°.</p>
<p>将 20-25 毫升的乙酸酐-硝酸溶液和约 1 克的固体混合物（随着温度的升高抑制酸酐和硝酸之间的反应并防止可能的危险冒烟）在反应器中搅拌。 烧瓶，通过将蒸汽引入水浴中，浴温迅速升高至约 80°。 内部温度一达到70-75°，就以每7ml液体加入4g固体混合物的速率逐渐加入固体和液体混合物。 在整个放热反应中，内部温度保持在 73-78°。开始时必须小心进行，但随着反应混合物体积的增加，当快速添加时，温度很容易保持在所需的范围内 作为每半分钟的一部分。 加入所有试剂后，将混合物在 75°搅拌 15 分钟。</p>
<p>Nearly from the start of the reaction the RDX precipi­tated from the reaction mixture in practically pure form as dense crystals. When the stirring was stopped, the RDX crystals settled like sand to the bottom of the flask, leaving the supernatant liquid practically clear.</p>
<p>The mixture was filtered while hot (60 °), washed with acetic acid and then with warm water, and dried; yield, 195-202.5 g. (61-63%) ; m.p. 203-204 ° with previous softening at 198° <sup>12</sup> When 5 g of the product was stirred with 25 ml. of 55% nitric acid at 70 ° for one-half hour, cooled and filtered, a 96% recovery of RDX with a m.p. of 205-206 ° was obtained.</p>
<p>几乎从反应开始，RDX就以几乎纯的形式从反应混合物中沉淀为致密晶体。停止搅拌时，RDX 晶体像沙子一样沉降到烧瓶底部，使上清液几乎透明。</p>
<p>趁热（60°）过滤混合物，用乙酸洗涤，然后用温水洗涤，干燥；产量，195-202.5 克。 (61-63%) ;熔点203-204°，预先在 198°软化 <sup>12</sup> 当 5 g 产品与 25 ml 一起搅拌时。 55% 硝酸在 70° 下半小时，冷却并过滤，RDX 的回收率为 96%，熔点获得了 205-206°。</p>
<p>When the reaction mixture was cooled in the course of one-half hour to 25 ° with stirring before being filtered, 225-235 g (70-73.5%) of product was obtained; m.p. 199-202 with previous softening at 191 °. Treatment with 55% nitric acid as above for one-half hour gave a product with 95% recovery melting at 203-204 ° with previous softening at 193 °; this represents a 67.5-70% yield.</p>
<p>When the reaction mixture was drowned by addition in one portion of 640 ml. of warm (50°) water with stirring, there was obtained 261 g. (81.5%) of colorless solid with mp. 180-185°. It was purified by heating 120 g of the material and a solution of 12 g of sodium acetate and 5 ml of concentrated aqueous ammonia in 600 ml of water on a steam-bath for sixteen hours under a reflux condenser. During the first few hours 5.5 ml. of concentrated aqueous ammonia was added as needed to keep the pH at 6-8; frequent tests were made during the first hour; weight of product, 106 g; m.p. 198-202°. A 7-g sample of this product was warmed with 35 ml of 70% nitric acid for fifteen minutes on a steam-bath with occasional swirling and then brought into solution over a micro burner. The beautiful colorless crystals of RDX obtained by adding an equal volume of water and allowing the mixture to cool weighed 6.47 g ; m.p. 203-204 ° with softening at 200 °.</p>
<p>Results similar to those described were obtained when all of the acetic anhydride was placed in the reaction flask at the start of the reaction. Another variation consisted in dissolving the ammonium nitrate in the 98% nitric acid; some gassing occurs and all of the yellow oxides of nitrogen are driven out. The resulting clear colorless solution does not attack the skin violently as does nitric acid alone. Solid hexamethylenetetramine was used in place of its salt. Although RDX was formed by mixing a solution of hexamethylenetetramine in acetic anhydride with a solu­tion of ammonium nitrate in nitric acid, the yield was not large.</p>
<p>在搅拌下将反应混合物在半小时内冷却至25°，然后过滤，得到225-235g（70-73.5%）产物；熔点199-202 之前在 191° 软化。如上用55%的硝酸处理半小时得到具有95%回收率的产物，在203-204°熔化并在193°预先软化；这代表 67.5-70% 的收率。</p>
<p>当反应混合物通过加入一份640毫升而被淹没时。在搅拌下加入温水（50°），得到261克。 (81.5%) 无色固体，mp. 180-185°。通过在回流冷凝器下在蒸汽浴上加热120g材料和12g乙酸钠和5ml浓氨水在600ml水中的溶液16小时来纯化。在最初的几个小时内 5.5 毫升。根据需要加入浓氨水以保持pH在6-8；在第一个小时内进行了频繁的测试；产品重量，106 克；熔点198-202°。用 35 毫升 70% 硝酸在蒸汽浴中加热 7 克该产品的样品 15 分钟，偶尔旋转，然后在微型燃烧器上溶解。通过加入等体积的水并让混合物冷却获得的美丽无色RDX晶体重6.47克；熔点203-204°，200°软化。</p>
<p>当在反应开始时将所有乙酸酐放入反应烧瓶中时，获得了与所述结果相似的结果。另一种变化是将硝酸铵溶解在 98% 的硝酸中。发生一些放气，所有黄色的氮氧化物都被排出。生成的透明无色溶液不会像单独使用硝酸那样猛烈攻击皮肤。使用固体六亚甲基四胺代替其盐。虽然RDX是通过将六亚甲基四胺的乙酸酐溶液与硝酸铵的硝酸溶液混合形成的，但产率并不大。</p>
<p><strong>Isolation of a High-Melting Nitrolysis Product.</strong>  —Theproduct obtained in 70-73.5% yield by filtration of the cooled anhydrous reaction mixture was warmed on a steam-bath with 55% nitric acid (5 ml. per gram) for about six hours, and the hot mixture was filtered. The crystals obtained from the chilled filtrate were isolated and warmed with 2-nitropropane (3.5 ml. per gram) in order to dissolve RDX, and the hot solution was decanted from the insoluble crystals of HMX ; m.p. 256° or higher, depending on the rate of heating. The compound can be recrystallized from 70% nitric acid without the forma­tion of yellow fumes.</p>
<p><strong>高熔点硝化产物的分离</strong>——  将冷却的无水反应混合物过滤得到的产率为 70-73.5% 的产物在蒸汽浴上用 55% 硝酸（每克 5 毫升）加热 大约六小时，过滤热的混合物。 从冷却的滤液中分离出晶体，并用 2-硝基丙烷（每克 3.5 毫升）加热以溶解 RDX，然后将热溶液从 HMX 的不溶性晶体中倾析出来； 熔点 256° 或更高，取决于加热速度。 该化合物可以从 70% 的硝酸中重结晶，而不会形成黄色烟雾。</p>
<p><strong>Preparation of a Nitration and Acetylation Product.—</strong> A mixture of 10.4 g. of hexamethylenetetramine dinitrate and 6.4 g. of ammonium nitrate was added to an ice-cold mixture of 25 ml. of acetic anhydride and 6.84 ml. of 98% nitric acid. The mixture was warmed slowly in the course of one-half hour to 75° with stirring and kept at that temperature for five minutes. Addition of water precipi­tated 13.8 g. of colorless solid; m. p. 140-145°. By recrystallization from acetone and ethyl acetate the product (BSX) was obtained as colorless plates or leaflets; m. p. 154-155°.</p>
<p><strong>硝化和乙酰化产物的制备</strong> ——将 10.4 g 六亚甲基四胺二硝酸盐和 6.4 g 硝酸铵的混合物加入到 25 ml 乙酸酐和 6.84 ml 98% 硝酸的冰冷混合物中。 混合物在搅拌下在半小时内缓慢升温至 75°，并在该温度下保持 5 分钟。 加水沉淀出13.8克无色固体； 熔点 140-145°。 通过从丙酮和乙酸乙酯中重结晶，得到产物（BSX），为无色片状或小叶状； 熔点 154-155°。</p>
<p><em>Anal.</em> Found: C, 26.4; H, 3.7; N, 24.8; molecular weight in acetone (Menzies’ method), about 350.</p>
<p><em>分析</em> 发现：C，26.4； H，3.7； N, 24.8; 丙酮中的分子量（孟席斯法），约 350。</p>
<p>The compound is readily decomposed by hot 70% nitric acid (fume-off) and by hot aqueous ammonia. A differ­ent product was obtained when propionic anhydride was substituted for the acetic anhydride.</p>
<p>该化合物很容易被 70% 的热硝酸（烟气）和热氨水分解。 当用丙酸酐代替乙酸酐时，得到不同的产物。</p>
<ol start="12">
<li>A safety shield should be placed between the observer and the melting point apparatus; this precaution is absolutely essential for the higher melting HMX. It is advisable to store the RDX under water, particularly when it is contaminated with the more sensitive forms of HMX.</li>
</ol>
<p>12.观察者与熔点仪之间应设置安全防护罩； 这种预防措施对于较高熔点的 HMX 是绝对必要的。 建议将 RDX 存放在水下，特别是当它被更敏感的 HMX 污染时。</p>
          <p><a href="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/1485/2">阅读完整话题</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/1485/2</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 05:03:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">mlmmlm.icu-post-1485-2</guid>
        <source url="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/1485.rss">ＲＤＸ 的合成工艺研究进展</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>ＲＤＸ 的合成工艺研究进展</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[azide]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a class="attachment" href="https://mlmmlm.icu/uploads/short-url/f2HBxfIWVbYg798avwpQoAdhs0L.pdf">RDX的合成工艺研究进展.pdf</a> (593.0 KB)</p>
          <p><a href="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/1485/1">阅读完整话题</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/1485/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 04:53:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">mlmmlm.icu-post-1485-1</guid>
        <source url="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/1485.rss">ＲＤＸ 的合成工艺研究进展</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
